Jontavius Caston | 318.953.1152 | j.caston91@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Professional Portfolio

Profile Summary

Information Security Analyst/Cybersecurity Specialist and U. S. Air Force veteran with active U.S. Secret Security Clearance ready to serve on a corporation's front lines battling cyber-attacks. Strengths include solving technical challenges, communicating effectively at all levels, and the ability to collaborate with systems engineers, network administrators, tech support personnel, software developers, and IT managers to analyze critical infrastructure and in the optimization of systems and software.

Education

MS in Data Science | Bellevue University | May 2020 | GPA 4.0

BS in Cybersecurity | Bellevue University | August 2018 | GPA 3.7

AS in Avionic Systems Technology | Community College of Air Force | February 2017

AS in Computer Technology Transfer and Information Assurance | Metropolitan Community College | November 2016 | GPA 3.8

Relevant Coursework: Network Security | Operational Security | Operating Systems and Mobile Device Security | Windows Operating Systems I | Java Programming I/II | Visual Basic.NET I | Intro to Database Design | Building Secure Environments | Structured Query Language SQL | Network and Information Security Basics | Network Attacks Intrusion | Boundary Protection | Information System Forensics and Legal | Principles of Physics | Intro to Cyber Threats, Technologies, and Security | Web Commerce and Application Security | Securing Access Control | Assessment and Audits | Data/Database Security | Statistics for Data Science | Data Mining | Data Exploration and Analysis | Data Preparation | Big Data | Applied Data Science

Technology Skills

Operating Systems: Windows 7/8/10, UNIX/Linux Ubuntu | Security: Snort, PhoneFactor/Azure, Access Control RFID, RSA SecurID | Networking: TACACS+/ACS, Pcap, Wireshark | Server/Storage: VMware, Citrix, Azure, SQL, Access, MySQL, Exchange, Apache | Routers/Switches: TCP/IP, VLAN | Programming Languages: Visual Basic, Visual Studio, Java I, Java II, HTML, Python, R, R Markdown, SQL, Jupyter Notebook, Tableau, Spark, PySpark, Power Bi

Cybersecurity Projects and Coursework

Cybersecurity coursework and independent projects created in home lab include: conducting investigations of security violations and breaches, performing forensic disk captures and analyses, and solving technical challenges. Skilled in identifying issues, finding workable solutions, and preparing remediation reports for management teams.

Professional Experience

Boeing Aerospace Company

Data Research Analyst

April 2019-Present

- Mining Datasets to find unseen connections between different systems
- Incorporates data into and maintains structured systems and coordinates program database requirements.
- Performs compliance activities including policy and procedure development, system/tool deployment and training delivery.
- Determine, define, and deploy predictive/ prescriptive analytic solutions to meet business objectives
- Choose best fit methods, define algorithms, validate and deploy models to achieve business results
- Investigate new analytical methodologies and technologies
- Perform necessary data preparation and enhancements to models

Gulfstream Aerospace

Avionics / Electrical Tech II

May 2017-Dec 2018

- Apply technical expertise, analytical ability, and creative problem-solving skills to lead team in completing all repairs and maintenance work to company standards.
- Provide highest quality of products by ensuring proper installation and maintaining good working order of
 equipment. Analyze equipment operating characteristics to isolate malfunctions in systems. Perform repair of
 single conductor, twisted pair, coax, triaxial, and quadrax wires.
- Diagnose malfunctions using technical order, schematics, wiring diagrams, integrated system test, and various test equipment.
- Inspect and verify operational status and configuration of avionics systems and software.

Key Initiatives & Results

- Exceeded customer product expectations by maintaining equipment and producing quality products.
- ► Contributed to reducing production downtime by ~15% through maintaining equipment and decreasing unnecessary maintenance. Contributed to safe and clean working environment for the team.

United States Air Force

Instrument and Flight Control Craftsman

August 2011-May 2017

- Review work orders and communicate with team and prior crew to assess work needs for the day.
- Perform repair of single conductor, twisted pair, coax, triaxial, and quadrax wires.
- Analyze equipment operating characteristics to isolate malfunctions in systems.

Kev Initiatives & Results

- ► Served 6 years as a Bomber and Special Mission Aircraft Avionics Systems Craftsman, performing instrument and flight control of OC-135B, RC-135S/U/V/W, TC-135V/W, and WC-135C/W. 5 years as a Supervisor and Trainer in the USAF.
- ► Completed extensive training and gained experience in electronic components, avionics systems, structural maintenance, and wiring. Inspected systems to ensure highest quality and proper working condition.
- ▶ Provided vision and guidance to a shop of more than 30 technicians ensuring proper training on project plans, maintenance repair work, and proper maintenance procedures.
- ► Exercised mechanical and design problem-solving skills in high-pressure environments.